[
{
  "question": "231. The tendency for long commercial vehicles to swing wide on turns is called:",
  "choices": [
    "Off-tracking.",
    "Hydroplaning.",
    "Fishtailing."
  ],
  "answer": "Off-tracking."
},
{
  "question": "232. What should you do if you get stuck on the railroad tracks?",
  "choices": [
    "Scream for help.",
    "Get out of your vehicle and away from the tracks.",
    "Stay in your vehicle."
  ],
  "answer": "Get out of your vehicle and away from the tracks."
},
{
  "question": "233. Which of these is a good thing to remember about drinking alcohol?",
  "choices": [
    "Alcohol first affects judgment and self-control.",
    "Small quantities of alcohol can improve reaction time.",
    "The driver can control how quickly the body rids itself of alcohol."
  ],
  "answer": "Alcohol first affects judgment and self-control."
},
{
  "question": "234. Which of these statements is true about medicines used to treat the common cold?",
  "choices": [
    "It can be used while driving as long as you only take half the regular dose.",
    "It should only be used when driving during the daytime.",
    "It often makes you sleepy, thus should not be used while driving."
  ],
  "answer": "It often makes you sleepy, thus should not be used while driving."
},
{
  "question": "235. The total weight of the powered unit, the trailer, and the cargo is called:",
  "choices": [
    "Gross vehicle weight.",
    "Gross combination weight.",
    "Gross axle weight."
  ],
  "answer": "Gross combination weight."
},
{
  "question": "236. Which piece of emergency equipment should be in your vehicle?",
  "choices": [
    "Circuit breakers.",
    "First Aid Kit.",
    "Warning devices for parked vehicles."
  ],
  "answer": "Warning devices for parked vehicles."
},
{
  "question": "237. Which of these statements is true about causes of vehicle fires?",
  "choices": [
    "Under-inflated tires will NOT cause a vehicle fire.",
    "Carrying a properly charged fire extinguisher will help prevent fires.",
    "Poor trailer ventilation can cause flammable cargo to catch on fire."
  ],
  "answer": "Poor trailer ventilation can cause flammable cargo to catch on fire."
},
{
  "question": "238. Which of these statements is true about vehicle fires?",
  "choices": [
    "If the cargo or box trailer catches on fire, open the doors as soon as you can.",
    "If your engine is on fire, open the hood as soon as you can.",
    "A burning tire should be cooled with water."
  ],
  "answer": "A burning tire should be cooled with water."
},
{
  "question": "239. Which of these statements is true about brakes?",
  "choices": [
    "Brakes absorb more heat to stop heavier vehicles.",
    "Brake drums cool very quickly when the vehicle is moving very fast.",
    "Brake fade is not caused by heat."
  ],
  "answer": "Brakes absorb more heat to stop heavier vehicles."
},
{
  "question": "240. Which of the following does not provide extra gears on some trucks?",
  "choices": [
    "Automatic transmissions.",
    "Auxiliary transmissions.",
    "Multi-speed rear axles."
  ],
  "answer": "Automatic transmissions."
},
  {
    "question": "241. Which of these Is not a danger when an automatic transmission is forced into a lower gear at a high speed?",
    "choices": [
      "Damage to the transmission.",
      "Loss of engine braking effect.",
      "Loss of steering control."
    ],
    "answer": "Loss of steering control."
  },
  {
    "question": "242. Which of these statements is true about backing heavy vehicles?",
    "choices": [
      "You should avoid backing whenever you can.",
      "Helpers should be out of sight and use only spoken signals to communicate with the driver.",
      "It's safer to back toward the right side of the vehicle."
    ],
    "answer": "You should avoid backing whenever you can."
  },
  {
    "question": "243. The distance you should look ahead while driving at highway speeds.",
    "choices": [
      "1/8 mile.",
      "1/4 mile.",
      "1/2 mile."
    ],
    "answer": "1/4 mile."
  },
  {
    "question": "244. The Commercial Driver's Handbook suggests several things to do when you pass a vehicle. Which of these is NOT one of them?",
    "choices": [
      "Lightly tap your horn if needed.",
      "At night, turn on your high beams while you pass the vehicle.",
      "Assume the other driver does not see you."
    ],
    "answer": "At night, turn on your high beams while you pass the vehicle."
  },
  {
    "question": "245. Which of these statements is true about speed management?",
    "choices": [
      "Shady parts of the road allow better traction than open areas.",
      "Road surfaces will freeze before bridges.",
      "On slippery roads, it takes longer to stop and is harder to turn without skidding."
    ],
    "answer": "On slippery roads, it takes longer to stop and is harder to turn without skidding."
  },
  {
    "question": "246. You are driving a heavy vehicle and must exit a highway using an off-ramp that curves downhill. You should:",
    "choices": [
      "Slow down to a safe speed before taking the curve.",
      "Slow down to the posted speed limit for the off-ramp.",
      "Wait until you are in the curve before downshifting."
    ],
    "answer": "Slow down to a safe speed before taking the curve."
  },
  {
    "question": "247. Which of these is a good thing to do when driving at night?",
    "choices": [
      "Drive slowly enough to stop within the range of your headlights.",
      "Look directly at oncoming headlights only briefly.",
      "Keep your instrument lights bright."
    ],
    "answer": "Drive slowly enough to stop within the range of your headlights."
  },
  {
    "question": "248. Which of these is NOT something you should do if your headlights are not working properly?",
    "choices": [
      "Clean the headlights.",
      "Leave your high beams on.",
      "Adjust the headlights."
    ],
    "answer": "Leave your high beams on."
  },
  {
    "question": "249. When roads are slippery you should:",
    "choices": [
      "Decrease the distance that you look ahead of your vehicle.",
      "Stop and test the traction while going up hills.",
      "Make turns as carefully as possible."
    ],
    "answer": "Make turns as carefully as possible."
  },
  {
    "question": "250. You should avoid driving through deep puddles or flowing water but if you cannot, which of these steps can help keep your brakes working?",
    "choices": [
      "Gently putting on the brakes while driving through the water.",
      "Turning on your brake heaters.",
      "Pressing both the brake pedal and the accelerator firmly after coming out of the water."
    ],
    "answer": "Gently putting on the brakes while driving through the water."
  },
  {
    "question": "251. Which of these is true about the radiator shutters and the winterfront?",
    "choices": [
      "The winterfront should be closed tightly.",
      "You should remove ice from the radiator shutters.",
      "The engine may overheat if the winterfront is left open."
    ],
    "answer": "You should remove ice from the radiator shutters."
  },
  {
    "question": "252. Which of these statements is NOT true about engine belts in hot weather?",
    "choices": [
      "Cracking is likely to occur but it is not a safety threat.",
      "You can check the tightness of belts by pressing on them.",
      "Loose belts will not turn the water pump and/or fan on properly."
    ],
    "answer": "Cracking is likely to occur but it is not a safety threat."
  },
  {
    "question": "253. What should you do if you see a hazard in the roadway?",
    "choices": [
      "Swerve around it and get back into your lane.",
      "Stop quickly and pull to the side of the road.",
      "Use your 4-way flashers or brake lights to warn others."
    ],
    "answer": "Use your 4-way flashers or brake lights to warn others."
  },
  {
    "question": "254. A car suddenly 'cuts' in front of you creating a hazard. What should you NOT do?",
    "choices": [
      "Honk and stay close behind the car.",
      "Slow down to prevent a crash.",
      "Signal and change lanes to avoid the car if possible."
    ],
    "answer": "Honk and stay close behind the car."
  },
  {
    "question": "255. Your vehicle has hydraulic brakes. When traveling on a level road, you press the brake pedal and find that it goes to the floor. Which of these statements is true?",
    "choices": [
      "The parking brake will not work because it is part of the same hydraulic system.",
      "Pumping the brake will generate enough pressure to stop the vehicle.",
      "Shifting into neutral will help slow the vehicle."
    ],
    "answer": "Pumping the brake will generate enough pressure to stop the vehicle."
  },
  {
    "question": "256. Bridge formulas permit:",
    "choices": [
      "Less maximum axle weight for axles that are close together.",
      "Less maximum axle weight for axles that are far apart.",
      "The same maximum axle weight for any axle spacing."
    ],
    "answer": "Less maximum axle weight for axles that are close together."
  },
  {
    "question": "257. You are checking your steering and exhaust systems in your pre-trip inspection. Which of these problems should be fixed before the vehicle is driven?",
    "choices": [
      "Oil on the tie rod.",
      "Grey smoke from the exhaust pipe.",
      "Steering play- more than 10% (2 inches on a 20 inch wheel)."
    ],
    "answer": "Steering play- more than 10% (2 inches on a 20 inch wheel)."
  },
  {
    "question": "258. Which of these items is NOT checked on a pre-trip inspection?",
    "choices": [
      "Whether all vehicle lights are working and clean.",
      "Cargo securement.",
      "Amount of fuel in the vehicle."
    ],
    "answer": "Amount of fuel in the vehicle."
  },
  {
    "question": "259. One can recognize hazardous materials by looking at the container's:",
    "choices": [
      "Label.",
      "Shape.",
      "Color."
    ],
    "answer": "Label."
  },
  {
    "question": "260. If you must stop on a hill in a two-way, two-lane road. How far back should you place your reflective triangles?",
    "choices": [
      "Within 250 feet behind the vehicle.",
      "Within 500 feet behind the vehicle.",
      "As far back as necessary, so that others can see your vehicle."
    ],
    "answer": "Within 500 feet behind the vehicle."
  },
  {
    "question": "261. Which of these is true about hours of service?",
    "choices": [
      "You must take a break after every two hours of driving.",
      "After 1,000 hours of service you will be exempt from certain regulations.",
      "You should balance your hours of service with enough sleep to keep you alert."
    ],
    "answer": "You should balance your hours of service with enough sleep to keep you alert."
  },
  {
    "question": "262. You should try to park your vehicle so:",
    "choices": [
      "You can pull forward when you leave.",
      "There is at least one curb next to your vehicle.",
      "Your vehicle is protected by trees or some overhang."
    ],
    "answer": "You can pull forward when you leave."
  },
  {
    "question": "263. Which of these is NOT a proper use of vehicle lights?",
    "choices": [
      "Turning on your headlights during the days when visibility is reduced.",
      "Flashing your brake lights to warn someone behind you that you are slowing down.",
      "Flashing your brake lights to stop someone from tailgating."
    ],
    "answer": "Flashing your brake lights to stop someone from tailgating."
  },
  {
    "question": "264. Which of the following is NOT a type of retarder?",
    "choices": [
      "Electric.",
      "Hydraulic.",
      "Robotic."
    ],
    "answer": "Robotic."
  },
  {
    "question": "265. What is the first thing you should try to do if your brakes fail while driving downhill?",
    "choices": [
      "Call or radio for help.",
      "Try to use your parking brake to stop.",
      "Get off the road as soon as possible."
    ],
    "answer": "Get off the road as soon as possible."
  },
  {
    "question": "266. When you drive in the mountains, you will have to use lower gears to drive safely down grades. Which of these does NOT affect your choice of gears?",
    "choices": [
      "Weight of the load.",
      "Tire tread type.",
      "Length of the grade."
    ],
    "answer": "Tire tread type."
  },
  {
    "question": "267. Which of these is NOT caused by rough acceleration?",
    "choices": [
      "Tire damage.",
      "Mechanical damage.",
      "Damage to the coupling."
    ],
    "answer": "Tire damage."
  },
  {
    "question": "268. Which of the following statements is true?",
    "choices": [
      "Most people are more alert at night than during the day.",
      "Most hazards are more easily seen at night than during the day.",
      "Many heavy vehicle accidents occur between midnight and 6 am."
    ],
    "answer": "Many heavy vehicle accidents occur between midnight and 6 am."
  },
  {
    "question": "269. Which of the following may be a sign of tire failure?",
    "choices": [
      "A loud hissing noise.",
      "Gentle thumping.",
      "Wheels fishtailing."
    ],
    "answer": "Wheels fishtailing."
  },
  {
    "question": "270. Which of these statements is NOT true?",
    "choices": [
      "Alcohol goes directly from the stomach to the bloodstream.",
      "A drinker can control how fast his or her body absorbs and gets rid of alcohol.",
      "BAC is determined by how fast you drink, how much you drink, and how much you weigh."
    ],
    "answer": "A drinker can control how fast his or her body absorbs and gets rid of alcohol."
  },
  {
    "question": "271. Optional safety equipment may include emergency phone numbers, tire chains, and:",
    "choices": [
      "Tire changing equipment.",
      "Red reflective triangles.",
      "Charged fire extinguisher."
    ],
    "answer": "Tire changing equipment."
  },
  {
    "question": "272. The braking effect of the engine is greatest when the engine is _ the governed RPM's and the transmission is in the — gears.",
    "choices": [
      "Above, lower.",
      "Below, higher.",
      "Near, lower."
    ],
    "answer": "Near, lower."
  },
  {
    "question": "273. The best drivers are those who watch and prepare for hazards. This is called being:",
    "choices": [
      "Defensive.",
      "Offensive.",
      "Objective."
    ],
    "answer": "Defensive."
  },
  {
    "question": "274. What will help keep an engine cool in hot weather?",
    "choices": [
      "Driving faster to force more air into the radiator.",
      "Running the air conditioner.",
      "Making sure the engine has the right amount of oil."
    ],
    "answer": "Making sure the engine has the right amount of oil."
  },
  {
    "question": "275. Which of these statements is true regarding the use of drugs while driving?",
    "choices": [
      "Prescription drugs are allowed as long as the doctor says the drugs will not affect safe driving ability.",
      "No prescription or non-prescription drugs are allowed at any time for any reason.",
      "Use of amphetamines, like 'speed,' is allowed as long as you are using the drugs to stay awake."
    ],
    "answer": "Prescription drugs are allowed as long as the doctor says the drugs will not affect safe driving ability."
  },
  {
    "question": "276. Which of these statements is true about warning other drivers of a stopped vehicle?",
    "choices": [
      "Move the rear reflective triangle back if the driver's vision is obscured to within 500 feet.",
      "Keep the vehicle's taillights on to warn other drivers.",
      "Put out your emergency warning devices within five minutes."
    ],
    "answer": "Move the rear reflective triangle back if the driver's vision is obscured to within 500 feet."
  },
  {
    "question": "277. If you have a heavy load that is slowing you down on an upgrade you should:",
    "choices": [
      "Exit the roadway until traffic is lighter.",
      "Drive on the shoulder so that others can pass easily.",
      "Shift into a lower gear."
    ],
    "answer": "Shift into a lower gear."
  },
  {
    "question": "278. Which of these statements is NOT true about backing a heavy vehicle?",
    "choices": [
      "You should use a helper and communicate with hand signals.",
      "You should back slowly until you slightly bump into the dock.",
      "You should back and turn toward the driver's side whenever possible."
    ],
    "answer": "You should back slowly until you slightly bump into the dock."
  },
  {
    "question": "279. In your mirror you see a car approaching from the rear. The next time you check your mirror you don't see the car. To change lanes you should:",
    "choices": [
      "Wait until you are sure the car isn't in your blind spot.",
      "Ease into the other lane slowly so the other car can get out of the way.",
      "Assume the car left the roadway and change lanes as normal."
    ],
    "answer": "Wait until you are sure the car isn't in your blind spot."
  },
  {
    "question": "280. What should you do if a car coming towards you at night keeps its high beams on?",
    "choices": [
      "Flash your high beams at the other driver.",
      "Slow down and look straight ahead in your lane.",
      "Look to the right edge of your lane or the right edge of the road."
    ],
    "answer": "Look to the right edge of your lane or the right edge of the road."
  }

]